<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content"><channel><title>Adventure Items</title><description>Find a D&amp;D adventure to give your character the perfect piece of swag.</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal09-07</guid><title>DDAL09-07 - The Diabolical Dive</title><description>Bowl of Commanding Water Elementals, a potion, 2 story awards, and one other item</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal09-07</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Diabolical Dive</h1><p>You have located the plans and drawn the infernal forces away from them. All that remains now is to dive below the river Styx and infiltrate Plagueshield Point without getting wet, setting off any alarms, or being followed. Piece of devil’s food cake. Part Three of the <em>Behind Infernal Lines</em> series of adventures.</p><p>A Four to Six-Hour Adventure for 5th through 10th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Bowl of Commanding Water Elementals <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Invisibility <em>rare</em></li><li>Soul Coin <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Thief of Infernal Knowledge</summary><p>You recovered additional intelligence that could allow you to avoid the movements of devilish forces later in your adventures. This Story Award will affect the later Tier 4 adventures.</p></details><details><summary>Savior of My Enemy’s Enemy</summary><p>You saved a group of drow slaves. Even though these devotees of Lolth aren’t good people themselves, you know how the saying goes: the enemy of my enemy is my friend. This Story Award will affect the later Tier 4 adventures.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal09-04</guid><title>DDAL09-04 - Day of the Devil</title><description>Periapt of Health, 2 potions, and one other item</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal09-04</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Day of the Devil</h1><p>The streets of Baldur’s Gate run red with blood. Old blood. The blood of Hellriders. Someone or something is punishing the children for the sins of the father and it’s time to put it to an end. Who and where is Gharizol? Part Three of the <em>Betrayal is in the Blood</em> series of adventures.</p><p>A Two-to-Four Hour Adventure for 1st through 4th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Periapt of Health <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Growth <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Soul Coin <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal09-03</guid><title>DDAL09-03 - Hungry Shadows</title><description>Gloves of Thievery and a scroll</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal09-03</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Hungry Shadows</h1><p>Bodies continue pile up, and the Flaming Fist still has nothing but a name. Thankfully, the perpetrator of the murders has slipped up and the Flaming Fist has captured one of their underlings, in turn, has revealed the presence of a cult hideout in the sewers beneath the city. The Flaming Fist has asked that you investigate. Are you up for the task? Part Two of the <em>Betrayal is in the Blood</em> series of adventures.</p><p>A Two-to-Four Hour Adventure for 1st through 4th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Gloves of Thievery <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Scroll of Protection (Fiends) <em>rare</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal09-02</guid><title>DDAL09-02 - Stopped at the Gate</title><description>Eyes of the Eagle and 2 potions</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal09-02</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Stopped at the Gate</h1><p>It’s been a long, arduous trip, but you’re finally here—Baldur’s Gate. You’re not out of peril yet, however, even if you’re leaving the lawless wilds behind you, the streets of the Gate still run red with blood. But you quickly find that arriving at the city wasn’t the biggest challenge at all, now you must convince the city’s rulers to grant asylum to you and those in your charge. Part One of the <em>Betrayal is in the Blood</em> series of adventures.</p><p>A Two-to-Four Hour Adventure for 1st through 4th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Eyes of the Eagle <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Poison <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal09-01</guid><title>DDAL09-01 - Escape from Elturgard</title><description>Amulet of Proof Against Detection and Location and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal09-01</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Escape from Elturgard</h1><p>Damnation! The entire city of Elturel—along with its denizens—have been drawn into Avernus, the first layer of the Nine Hells! While those fortunate enough to have been outside of the city’s walls have been spared that fate, they’re not yet out of danger! The refugees formed a caravan bound for the nearby city of Baldur’s Gate. Can you keep them safe from devils, bandits, and one another until they reach safety?</p><p>Four, One-Hour Introductory Mini-adventures for 1st and 2nd Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Amulet of Proof Against Detection and Location <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Cooler Heads Prevail</summary><p>You have spared the murderer, Vollis, in the hopes that she will be brought to justice upon arriving in Baldur’s Gate.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddep08-03</guid><title>DDEP08-03 - Last Orders at the Yawning Portal</title><description>Animated Shield, Ring of Invisibility, Rope of Climbing, Winged Boots, and 3 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddep08-03</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Last Orders at the Yawning Portal</h1><p>Durnan has closed the Yawning Portal and mysteriously disappeared back down the well into Undermountain. His old adventuring companion Mirt has hung up his tankard and set off to find him, but he can’t do it alone. Champions gather from afar to answer his call and rescue one of the city’s most iconic heroes. Will YOU join them? A Three-Hour D&amp;D Epics™ adventure for Tier 1-4 characters. Optimized for APL 3, 8, 13, and 18.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Animated Shield <em>very rare</em></li><li>Ring of Invisibility <em>legendary</em></li><li>Rope of Climbing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Winged Boots <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Deep Delver</summary><p>Your successes in the dungeons of Undermountain have brought you glory in the city above. You earn any additional point of renown. Whenever you return to Waterdeep following a successful expedition into the dungeons of Undermountain, you gain a free healing potion.</p></details><details><summary>Tavern Hero</summary><p>Your actions were noteworthy in rescuing Durnan the Innkeeper from the dungeons of Undermountain. The proprietor of the Yawning Portal has granted you free accommodation and drinks in his inn for the rest of your life and commissioned a portrait of your group to hang in the taproom until the end of time.</p></details><details><summary>Sold Soul</summary><p>Your soul has been promised to Breccia of the Growling Groghouse. If you later die, she claims your soul and uses it for own mysterious purposes. The only way you can be restored to life is via a <em>true resurrection</em> spell, after which this award is removed.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal08-09</guid><title>DDAL08-09 - Fangs and Frogs</title><description>Wand of Lightning Bolts, 2 scrolls, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal08-09</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Fangs and Frogs</h1><p>Your chase to wipe out the vampires of Undermountain leads to the Slitherswamp. The master vampire is close at hand! Part Three of the <em>Vampire Hunt</em> trilogy.</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for Tier 2 Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Wand of Lightning Bolts <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Dispel Magic <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Suggestion <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Monstrous Merger</summary><p>You decided to take a chance and touch or drink the multicolored water that spilled from a broken fountain in Arcturia’s abandoned laboratory. Doing so has changed you forever. Arcturia was a master of transmutation and she must have used this water to assist her in her unholy experiments. While you no longer carry the negative effects associated with this, it seems the physical trait you manifested still lingers. This story award can only be removed by a <em>remove curse</em>.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal08-08</guid><title>DDAL08-08 - Crypt of the Dark Kiss</title><description>Ring of Resistance (Fire)</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal08-08</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Crypt of the Dark Kiss</h1><p>Are there actually vampires in Undermountain? The Baron of Blood demands that you find out! Part Two of the <em>Vampire Hunt</em> trilogy.</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for Tier 2 Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ring of Resistance (Fire) <em>rare</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal08-07</guid><title>DDAL08-07 - Into the Dark</title><description>Mace of Smiting and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal08-07</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Into the Dark</h1><p>When one of the Lords of Waterdeep asks you to root out a threat to the city, you respond to the call. Prepare for a foray into Undermountain. Part One of the <em>Vampire Hunt</em> trilogy.</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for Tier 2 Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Mace of Smiting <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Endless Bluetooth Ale</summary><p>If a way was discovered to set up a supply of the blue lichen to the Yawning Portal, Durnan provides all the Bluetooth Ale the characters can drink whenever they visit. Brewed from the blue lichen grown on the skeletons of dwarves left for dead in the Stonebone Mines, bluetooth ale is a truly unique beverage.</p><p>The strong dwarven-style ale is a rich sapphire color and has a faint earthy taste. While the ale lacks most of the special properties of the blue lichen, it still can turn the imbibers teeth (and bones) temporarily blue.</p><p>The ale functions as an ingested poison. The drinker must succeed on a DC 12 Constitution saving throw, or their skeleton turns a dark shade of blue for 24 hours.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal07-02</guid><title>DDAL07-02 - Over the Edge</title><description>Scroll of Protection (Aberrations), 14 potions, 2 scrolls, a spellbook, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal07-02</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Over the Edge</h1><p>In response to a new but as-of-yet-unnamed threat, the factions have called upon adventurers to venture into the jungle in search of a location for a new base of operations. As such, you have been charged with scouting several locations to assess their viability. Surely something so trivial as a scouting mission couldn’t go wrong?</p><p>Five One-Hour Adventures for 5th–10th Level Characters</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>1 x Potion of Animal Friendship <em>uncommon</em></li><li>4 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Invulnerability <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Poison <em>uncommon</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Resistance (Psychic) <em>uncommon</em></li><li>4 x Potion of Water Breathing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Scroll of Protection (Aberrations) <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Remove Curse <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Tongues <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Naga's Spellbook: </strong>control water, fire shield, and ice storm</li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Honorary Clan Member</summary><p>For your assistance in saving the lives of the peaceful yuan-ti clan known as the Misty Cliff clan, they have made you an honorary member of their clan. If you are in need and a member of the clan is nearby, they provide whatever help they can. The same is expected of you if the clan requires assistance.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddep06-01</guid><title>DDEP06-01 - Relics of Khundrukar</title><description>Durgeddin’s Fist (Mace of Terror), Durgeddin’s Unbreakable Auspice (Adamantine Armor), Magic Weapon, +1, Wand of Binding, 7 potions, a scroll, 5 story awards, and one other item</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddep06-01</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Relics of Khundrukar</h1><p>Khundrukar held many fine implements of war in its heyday, many of them now lost to time. Clues point to some of long dead Master Smith Durgeddin’s handiwork in the service of sinister forces that bid their time deep in the Underdark. Reclaim the riches of Khundrukar from the darkness if you dare.</p><p>A Four-Hour Epic Adventure for 1st–4th and 5th–10th Level Characters</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Durgeddin’s Fist (Mace of Terror) <em>rare</em></li><li>Durgeddin’s Unbreakable Auspice (Adamantine Armor) <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Magic Weapon, +1 <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Wand of Binding <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Elixir of Health <em>rare</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Invulnerability <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Lightning Resistance <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Stoneskin <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Friend of Mirabar</summary><p>The Council of Sparkling Stones recognizes your courage and leadership during this time of adversity by granting you a royal badge of Mirabar, depicted as an upright, double-bladed axe with a pointed haft and a flaring, flat base. This badge grants the wearer advantage on all Charisma (Persuasion) checks in Mirabar, Sundabar, and Citadel Adbar, and may stay in the city for up to 60 days at a luxurious lifestyle with no cost. The bearer may also purchase one suit of nonmagical armor for half the listed retail price in the PHB during any of those downtime days.</p></details><details><summary>A Gnome and His Box</summary><p>You helped Gurdin Gloomhands solve an old puzzle box he’s struggled with for decades. As a reward, Gurdrin cuts a gorgeous ruby inset in a silver pendant. The center of the ruby glitters with mesmerizing patters when exposed to light. One time, and one time only, you may use the ruby to cast maze as the wizard spell of the same name. The magic of the pendant is then expended and it becomes a beautiful piece of jewelry worth 150 gp.</p></details><details><summary>Pyric Victory</summary><p>Despite your best efforts, the Mirabaran forces suffered grievous casualties fighting Clan Xornbane. You are feted as a hero by the survivors, but the trauma remains. The next time you fight duergar, derro, or any fiends you gain advantage in the first round of combat from the fury you feel towards your foes. However, the first time an ally is reduced to 0 hit points or fewer in combat you are frightened for one round as the memories come flooding back.</p></details><details><summary>A Sapper’s Best Friend</summary><p>Your exceptional prowess and courage saved every single one of the sappers sent to blow up the trench system in Grave Dust Cavern. Your steely- eyed determination allows you treat one failed saving throw vs an effect that imposes the frightened condition as a success. You also gain the honorary title of Sapper from the dwarves of Mirabar along with an engraved pewter hip flask filled with potent dwarven brandy, enough to get one person right and proper drunk.</p></details><details><summary>Fratricide</summary><p>Dumathoin, Keeper of Secrets Under the Mountain, sees what you did. Whenever you are underground or in an area of darkness, natural or magical, you feel Dumathoin’s gaze upon you. You are subject to critical hits on a roll of 19-20 and the damage is maximized in these conditions. Contact resource@dndadventurersleague.org to learn how to atone for your misdeeds.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal06-02</guid><title>DDAL06-02 - The Redemption of Kelvan</title><description>Boots of Speed, 2 potions, and a spellbook</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal06-02</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Redemption of Kelvan</h1><p>A strange, foreign wizard calling himself Kelvan has appeared at the same time a mountain materializes out of thin air. He asks you to recover the Gloomblade from a Netherese ruin in order to help him with his research into this strange new mountain.</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 5th–10th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Boots of Speed <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Diminution <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Shadow Tome: </strong>bestow curse, blight, blindness/deafness, comprehend languages, darkness, darkvision, dispel magic, fear, Evard's black tentacles, find familiar, and witch bolt</li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-16</guid><title>DDAL05-16 - Parnast Under Siege</title><description>Headband of Intellect, 2 potions, and 4 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-16</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Parnast Under Siege</h1><p>Despite the adventurers’ best efforts, more creatures joined under Bad Fruul’s banner. No longer content to simply attack caravans or isolated homesteads, the hill giant warlord descends upon Parnast at the head of a great force of humanoids. SEER warns the adventurers (directly now) in time to rally the town and prepare defenses, but a heroic effort is required to break the siege.</p><p>A Four-Hour Adventure for 1st–4th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Headband of Intellect <em>uncommon</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Giant Strength (Hill) <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Giant Horde Breaker!</summary><p>The tale of your defense of Parnast has spread far and wide. Charisma checks made when dealing with goodly folk who have had trouble with giants in the past are made with advantage. Similarly, any Charisma (Deception, Intimidation, or Persuasion) check you make against a non-good-aligned giant is made with disadvantage.</p></details><details><summary>Giant Toenails</summary><p>If the characters scavenged toe nails from Bad Fruul, SEER brews a <em>potion of hill giant strength</em>. A few ingredients are needed and require the adventures to spend 10 downtime days (and associated living expense costs).</p></details><details><summary>Rue's Harvest</summary><p>If characters interacted with Sylas during the adventure he offers them the opportunity to purchase the last harvest of herb garden.</p><p>Each character can gain supplies to create a maximum of five of any of the following items listed below in any combination—even if they don’t have the necessary tools and proficiencies. The crafting rules found in the Player's Handbook (downtime and lifestyle cost still apply).</p><ul><li>Antitoxin</li></ul><ul><li>Perfume</li></ul><ul><li>Alchemist’s fire</li></ul><ul><li>Potion of healing</li></ul><ul><li>Ink</li></ul><ul><li>Poison (basic)</li></ul><ul><li>Dye (lavender)</li></ul><ul><li>Bath oil</li></ul></details><details><summary>Savior of Parnast</summary><p>You are always welcome in Parnast, while in town you will not spend any gold on food or lodging (lifestyle must still be paid for any downtime days spent).</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-15</guid><title>DDAL05-15 - Reclamation</title><description>Pennant of the Vind Rune, a potion, and a scroll</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-15</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Reclamation</h1><p>SEER has been rescued along with Ulcaster, the infamous Archmage that founded a wizard’s school that is now in ruins in the foot hills of The Cloud Peaks. However, while leaving to get the two to safety a cloud ship arrived, unloading a shipload of pirates on the ruins. SEER knows what they are after and needs the heroes to stop them and their leader.</p><p>A Four-Hour Adventure for 11th–16th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Pennant of the Vind Rune <em>very rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Superior Healing <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Stoneskin <em>rare</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-14</guid><title>DDAL05-14 - Reeducation</title><description>Opal of the Ild Rune, Orb of the Stein Rune, and 2 potions</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-14</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Reeducation</h1><p>HSING bears foul news: SEER has been captured. While exploring the ruins of Ulcaster in search of knowledge pertaining to runes (or perhaps even how to create them), they were separated and now the pseudodragon fears the worst. Without SEER’s guidance, the efforts of the assembled factions in these recent events may all be for naught!</p><p>A Four-Hour Adventure for 11th–16th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Opal of the Ild Rune <em>rare</em></li><li>Orb of the Stein Rune <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Giant Strength (Cloud) <em>very rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Superior Healing <em>rare</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-13</guid><title>DDAL05-13 - Jarl Rising</title><description>The Shroud of the Mourning Warrior (Scale Mail, +1) and 3 potions</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-13</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Jarl Rising</h1><p>The frost giants of the Ice Mountains have long held to the belief that a great Jarl will one day step forward to unite the families as Konung (king). With the Ordning shattered, Jarl Ryndölg believes that if he can locate Hartkiller’s Horn, a legendary artifact among giant-kind, he could be the one. He may very well have found what he is looking for. A great clarion call has echoed across the Hartsvale for two days, and the giants are all marching north, has Ryndölg done just that?</p><p>A Four-Hour Adventure for 5th–10th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>The Shroud of the Mourning Warrior (Scale Mail, +1) <em>rare</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Superior Healing <em>rare</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-12</guid><title>DDAL05-12 - Bad Business in Parnast</title><description>Gauntlets of Ogre Power, a potion, and one other item</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-12</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Bad Business in Parnast</h1><p>Bad Fruul and his minions have been threatening to overtake the town of Parnast for some time, and intelligence provided by SEER (via HSING) confirms that an attack is imminent. Despite this, the town is at risk from within as internal politics threaten to tear it apart. It is up to adventurers to resolve the infighting in Parnast and prepare the town for the hill giant’s onslaught.</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 1st–4th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Gauntlets of Ogre Power <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Oil of Slipperiness <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-11</guid><title>DDAL05-11 - Forgotten Traditions</title><description>Opal of the Ild Rune, 4 story awards, and 3 other items</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-11</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Forgotten Traditions</h1><p>The origin of runes has long been lost to the majority of sages and wizards, save those with giant blood. However, with the shattering of the Ordning, the magic of runes has once again emerged into the Realms. Adventurers must delve into a ruined complex beneath the Spine of the World, suspected by SEER to be the birthplace of that arcane tradition.</p><p>A Four-Hour Adventure for 5th–10th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Opal of the Ild Rune <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Red Crystal (Potion of Giant Strength (Fire)) <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Blue Crystal (Potion of Superior Healing) <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Black Crystal (Spell Scroll of Antilife Spell) <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Dreamwalker (downtime)</summary><p>Kryshilir has taught you to look beyond the veil of the world and navigate your dreams. By spending 25 downtime days, you travel to the Seven Stones and meditate under Kryshilir’s whispered guidance. Upon completing this downtime activity, you gain the <strong>Dreamwalker</strong> story award (below).</p></details><details><summary>Dreamwalker</summary><p>Your meditations have granted you the gift of foresight. Upon receiving this story award, roll a d20 and record the number rolled. Once, you can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with the number you rolled. You must choose to do so before the roll. Once you have used this story award in this fashion, remove it. This story award may be earned again as often as you like, but you must complete the <strong>Dreamwalker</strong> downtime activity (above) each time and may not do so again until you no longer possess this story award.</p></details><details><summary>Student of Stone (downtime)</summary><p>Illsenstaad has chosen you and you alone to complete his life’s work and put his soul to rest. By spending a total of 365 downtime days (these need not be spent all at once) possessed by Illsenstaad, allowing him to tell his stories and carve them into the living rock of Hotun-Shûl, you gain the <strong>Student of Stone</strong> story award (below). If you are a dwarf, possess the Guild Artisan (mason or stonecutter) background, or are otherwise proficient in mason’s tools; you complete this in half the normal time.</p></details><details><summary>Student of Stone</summary><p>You have studied under the tutelage of Illsenstaad, a legendary stone giant loremaster and stone carver. You gain the benefit of the dwarven Stonecunning trait. If you already possess the Stonecunning trait, you triple your proficiency bonus instead of doubling it. In addition, you also gain proficiency in mason’s tools and the Giant language if you are not already proficient.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-10</guid><title>DDAL05-10 - Giant Diplomacy</title><description>Ring of Jumping, 2 potions, and 3 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-10</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Giant Diplomacy</h1><p>SEER has learned of an attempt to intimidate Gralm, an ettin, and his followers into joining Bad Fruul’s army. HSING comes forth to communicate that she wants you to see if you can find some way to either insure Gralm remains neutral, or to encourage the creature to challenge Bad Fruul to single combat in the hopes that he might wrest control of the hill giant’s forces and turn them back from Parnast.</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 1st–4th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ring of Jumping <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Defenders of Parnast</summary><p>You have helped forge a treaty between the city of Parnast and the Ettin Gralm. Citizens will buy you a drink or meal and many toast to your name.</p></details><details><summary>Greater Defenders of Parnast</summary><p>You have shown your selflessness time and again to the citizens of Parnast. While in Parnast, everyone opens their doors and pantries to you offering a 10% discount on goods and healing services.</p></details><details><summary>Satyr Training</summary><p>Prince Thornacious has heard more of your great deeds through his servant Blassios. The latter invites you to come on a “vision quest” with him in the Forgotten Forest. If you do, you may spend 5 downtimes days to engage in revelry and seeking out your inner self. Once, if you fail a saving throw against poison, you may call upon your fey teachings to succeed on the saving throw, instead.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-09</guid><title>DDAL05-09 - Durlag's Tomb</title><description>Skeggöx (Battleaxe, +3), 2 potions, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-09</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Durlag's Tomb</h1><p>East of Beregost, nestled in the outskirts of the Wood of Sharp Teeth, Durlag’s Tower has intrigued and yet stymied adventurers for decades. Stuffed full of mechanical traps and arcane wards, and rumored to be inhabited by fiends, very few have managed to extract any REAL treasure from the former home of Durlag Trollkiller. However, a powerful item in the ancient fight against the giants is said to be housed there, and the cloud giant Baron Rajiram has committed significant resources toward recovering it. After a pleasant tea in her garden, SEER calls upon you to beat him there and put a stop to his efforts! Part of 2 of 2.</p><p>A 4-Hour Adventure for 11th–16th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Skeggöx (Battleaxe, +3) <em>very rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Invulnerability <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Superior Healing <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Favor of Candlekeep</summary><p>You surrender of the copper tablet to the acolytes of Oghma at Candlekeep has them overjoyed. The Great Readers spend many weeks poring over the ancient artifact’s hidden meanings and may one day puzzle out where the missing section is located.</p><p>The next time you visit Candlekeep or interact with the faithful of Oghma, any Charisma ability checks you make are made with advantage.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-08</guid><title>DDAL05-08 - Durlag's Tower</title><description>Staff of Thunder and Lightning, Quasit's Essence, 4 potions, a scroll, and 3 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-08</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Durlag's Tower</h1><p>East of Beregost, nestled in the outskirts of the Wood of Sharp Teeth, Durlag’s Tower has intrigued and yet stymied adventurers for decades. Stuffed full of mechanical traps and arcane wards, and rumored to be inhabited by fiends, very few have managed to extract any REAL treasure from the former home of Durlag Trollkiller. However, a powerful item in the ancient fight against the giants is said to be housed there, and the cloud giant Baron Rajiram has committed significant resources toward recovering it. After a pleasant tea in her garden, SEER calls upon you to beat him there and put a stop to his efforts!</p><p>A Four-Hour Adventure for 11th–16th level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Staff of Thunder and Lightning <em>very rare</em></li><li>Quasit's Essence <em>unique</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Giant Strength (Frost) <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Invulnerability <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Speed <em>very rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Superior Healing <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Greater Invisibility <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Favor of SEER</summary><p>If the characters choose to not sell the jade dagger, they may instead turn it over to SEER. If they do, they all earn her admiration, as this very dagger was lost during an expedition that, in her words, “went poorly”. The blade is a family heritage item and all that remains of her long-lost uncle, whom she refuses to name directly. SEER is willing to provide a character that has this story award with one spell scroll of second level or lower. If the character is a member of the Lords’ Alliance, they can instead choose a spell scroll of up to third level. If the character is a member of the Lords’ Alliance and is rank four or higher, they may instead choose a spell scroll of level 3 or lower and also receive a <em>potion of heroism</em>. Any spell chosen for this reward must be on the wizard spell list and cannot be a ritual. Once a reward is chosen, strike out this story award.</p></details><details><summary>Traitor to Your Faction</summary><p>Lords’ Alliance and Zhentarim faction members that falsified evidence of their missions or failed their missions suffer a terrible blow to their reputation. After this adventure, the character must forfeit the next two renown points that they would gain; once this forfeiture is complete, strike out this story award.</p></details><details><summary>Vergadain’s Firespirits</summary><p>Vergadain, a dwarven deity of wealth and trickery, was known for his favored drink; as clear as water and smelled of honey and cane sugar, but was in truth an incredibly potent liquor that put standard dwarven spirits to shame. He would sometimes challenge unknowing humans and elves to drinking contents, where he would slyly swap in sweetened water while his opponent would down drink after drink of this highly-flammable liquid. It rarely ended well for them. And now you have the recipe!</p><p>You may spend 60 downtime days to craft one barrel of firespirits. Each batch requires special sweet herbs from Bitter-root’s copse near Durlag’s Tower and 100 gp worth of other materials, including aged dwarven spirits blessed by a dwarven priest. If you find yourself in possession of campaign documentation that bestows ownership of a distillery, this time and gold cost is reduced by half.</p><p>Each barrel contains approximately 30 gallons of firespirits, and can be sold for 1,000 gp. Alternately, as this is a rare elixir; it may be worth a significant amount to Fai Chen, certain high-ranking lords, or other purveyors of such fineries. Additionally, if you give a nip of firespirits (just a wee one) to a dwarf, all Charisma (Persuasion) checks made with them are made with advantage for the next hour.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-07</guid><title>DDAL05-07 - Chelimber's Descent</title><description>Wand of Webs, 2 scrolls, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-07</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Chelimber's Descent</h1><p>Deep in the Marsh of Chelimber lie the ruins of a great wizard’s tower. SEER has received intelligence, which she imparts via her emissary Hsing, that deep beneath the marsh in the remains of an old tower is knowledge of older magics. This could be just what Parnast needs to resist the onslaught of Bad Fruul and his armies!</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 1st–4th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Wand of Webs <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Lesser Restoration <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Tongues <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Faction Copyist</summary><p>Any character may spend ten downtime days assisting their faction by copying the texts retrieved for SEER. Upon completing this downtime activity, the character may copy one spell from the <em>Elemental Evil Player’s Companion</em> of a level they can cast for their spellbook.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-06</guid><title>DDAL05-06 - Beneath the Fetid Chelimber</title><description>Ring of Swimming</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-06</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Beneath the Fetid Chelimber</h1><p>The ruined wizard tower in the Marsh of Chelimber may hold a clue to defeating the superintelligent hill giant, Bad Fruul, and prevent him troubling the town of Parnast. To find the tower, adventurers must overcome the watery magic of the fetid marsh and discover or clear a route to the ruins of a previously lost tower.</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 1st–4th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ring of Swimming <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-05</guid><title>DDAL05-05 - A Dish Best Served Cold</title><description>Cloak of Displacement, 2 potions, and 3 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-05</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>A Dish Best Served Cold</h1><p>Stagwick’s long-standing peace with giant-kind is threatened as a patrol of Blood Riders spark a feud with a local tribe of giants. With word of strange activity coming from the Ice Spires, Good King Hartwick can’t be too careful. Can you quench the giants’ thirst for revenge?</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 5th–10th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Cloak of Displacement <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Giant Strength (Frost) <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Adventurer? More Like Bad-venturer!</summary><p>If Burleigh dies or is not freed within the time frame provided by Scövja, word spreads that the same adventurers who were telling tales of their heroic deeds at the Weary Giant Inn failed at some simple task and have put the region in danger. As long as you possess this story award, you have disadvantage on Charisma (Intimidation) and (Persuasion) checks made to influence any citizen of Hartsvale.</p></details><details><summary>Frontier Friend</summary><p>If the characters free Burleigh by convincing Scarn Mikel to let him go peacefully, the Blood Riders gain a new respect for the Frontier Scouts. As a result, the riders stop bullying the scouts and they stay out of one another’s way. As long as you possess this story award, you have advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) and (Persuasion) checks made to influence any member of the Frontier Scouts.</p></details><details><summary>Scarn Slayer</summary><p>Characters who kill Scarn Mikel have their names whispered on the lips of every citizen in Hartsvale. As long as you possess this story award, you have advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks made to influence any citizen of Hartsvale, but any Blood Riders you come across immediately treat you as hostile.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-04</guid><title>DDAL05-04 - In Dire Need</title><description>Mithral Splint Armor, +1, 2 potions, and 3 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-04</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>In Dire Need</h1><p>An expedition of dwarf warriors from Citadel Adbar finds itself isolated and besieged by Ice Spire ogres and their allies. They require immediate relief or they risk being destroyed to a dwarf. SEER has directed you to their location in the hopes that you can rescue the dwarves and save their precious cargo, a tablet bearing secrets of ancient rune magic.</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 5th–10th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Mithral Splint Armor, +1 <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Climbing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Heroism <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>SEER’s Delivery Service</summary><p>You successfully delivered the rune tablet into the hands of the Lord’s Alliance for study, much to their gratitude. You gain advantage on ability checks that involve interacting with NPC members of the Lord’s Alliance. Additionally, you gain disadvantage on ability checks that involve interacting with NPCs that specifically oppose the Lord’s Alliance.</p></details><details><summary>Heroes of Citadel Adbar</summary><p>Your brave rescue of the Frostbite Platoon has earned you fame and favor within the dwarven citadel. While the citadel normally shuts out visitors, you are granted access to the citadel’s upper reaches. You gain advantage on ability checks that involve interacting with dwarves from Citadel Adbar, regardless of where you travel.</p></details><details><summary>Ire of the Frost Giants</summary><p>You either inadvertently or purposefully destroyed a frost giant holy site. Whether or not anyone witnessed the act, word of your “accomplishment” still travels and reaches the frost giant communities throughout the Realms. You gain disadvantage on ability checks that involve interacting with frost giants. Additionally, you gain advantage on ability checks that involve interacting with NPCs that specifically oppose frost giants.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-03</guid><title>DDAL05-03 - Uninvited Guests</title><description>Brooch of Shielding, a potion, and 3 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-03</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Uninvited Guests</h1><p>The Shrine of the Axes has been restored and Raggnar Redtooth, who previously conspired with dragon cultists, is trying to restore his reputation in Parnast by sponsoring a feast. There is just one thing he needs, meat for his feast. Game is supposed to be plentiful in the Weathercote Wood, but the townsfolk are all busy with their own work, and the minions of Bad Fruul are still out there causing trouble. What can go wrong on a simple hunt?</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 1st–4th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Brooch of Shielding <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>A Giant Challenge</summary><p>You have earned the respect of Prince Thornacious. He challenges you to befriend a giant, as he has done with you, (<em>Huge</em> sized humanoid), without using charm effects. If you do, (DMs judgement), you may spend five downtime days to return to Thornacious, who uses Heart Sight to tell if you are true of heart. He bestows upon you the title: Adoness (Peacekeeper). This title grants you advantage on Charisma ability checks with good aligned fey.</p></details><details><summary>Defenders of Parnast</summary><p>You have repelled the enemies of Parnast and instilled confidence in the people. You’ll never sleep in a barn again while in Parnast. Everyone opens their doors to you.</p></details><details><summary>Glory Before Goodwill</summary><p>You chose to put personal glory above saving a villager of Parnast that was in need. Until you spend 10 downtime days repairing your reputation with the village, you have disadvantage on all Charisma ability checks and are charged 50% higher rate for all goods and services, except at the Golden Tankard, where Raggnar understands that tough decisions must occasionally be made.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-02</guid><title>DDAL05-02 - The Black Road</title><description>Bracers of Archery and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-02</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Black Road</h1><p>Caravans are having a difficult time getting through to Parnast via the Black Road. Organized attacks by orcs and other monstrous humanoids working in concert with one another have folks baffled. Little do they know that an unusually intelligent hill giant, going by the name of Bad Fruul is to blame. SEER has sent her emissary Hsing, to task your group to accompany a caravan with a very special cargo destined for the Shrine of Axes in Parnast, and to figure out who is responsible.</p><p>A Two Hour Adventure for 1st–4th Level Characters</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Bracers of Archery <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Friend on the Black Road</summary><p>You aided the caravan master Azam on a perilous journey along the Black Road. If you find yourself needing to travel the Black Road or transport something discretely, Azam will provide it safely once for free.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-01</guid><title>DDAL05-01 - Treasure of the Broken Hoard</title><description>3 potions, 2 scrolls, 5 story awards, and one other item</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal05-01</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Treasure of the Broken Hoard</h1><p>A famous relic hunter seeks adventurers to help her find caches of treasure hidden by the now-defeated followers of the Cult of the Dragon. Her maps and notes may lead the way to great wealth—or a terrible death. And do other parties have designs on the treasure as well?</p><p>Five 1-Hour Mini-Adventures for 1st &amp; 2nd Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>1 x Alchemist's fire (flask) <em>common</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Comprehend Languages <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Disguise Self <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Blooddrinker the Bear</summary><p>Through care and patience, you now have a bear pet. She is, however, the size of a small housecat. She cannot attack, defend, distract, aid, or otherwise play any role in combat. She can be taught to do simple tricks if treated well and if you spend 20 down time days training her.</p></details><details><summary>Friend of Prrrt</summary><p>You helped alleviate the suffering of a galeb duhr named Prrrt. It tells others of its kind of your kindness, garnering you a positive reputation among elemental earth creatures. As an action, you can attempt a DC 10 Charisma (Persuasion) check to convince earth creatures of the elemental type not to attack you. As long as you do not attack the creature or other elemental earth creatures, it targets others. This, however, does not protect your allies. You lose this story aware if you attack or otherwise harm an elemental earth creature.</p></details><details><summary>Victim of Greed</summary><p>You were stung by greed, and your soul has been infected by the deadly sin. When you’re in the presence of great wealth (in the form of coins or gems/jewelry worth over 1,000 gp), you are stunned until the end of your first turn, as your mind reels at such great wealth. This can be removed with a <em>remove curse</em>.</p></details><details><summary>Hated by Giants</summary><p>You unwisely removed one of the sacred plates of Annam from his shrine. You are now cursed. Giants who see you know that you have offended the greatest of their gods, and they target you before your allies in a fight. They also have advantage on attacks against you. This can be removed with a <em>remove curse</em>. You also have possession of one or more plates, but no one seems to want to buy them from you.</p></details><details><summary>Friend of Kraddokk</summary><p>You talked with the storm giant Kraddokk and did not desecrate the shrine of Annam. He tells his friends about your interaction with him. This friendship might bear fruit at a later date.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-14</guid><title>DDAL04-14 - The Dark Lord</title><description>Bracers of Defense, 4 potions, a scroll, 2 spellbooks, and 3 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-14</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Dark Lord</h1><p>The enemy is revealed, but time short and if you are not successful in your mission to Mount Baratok, love will never die. Part fourteen and the finale of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Bracers of Defense <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Animal Friendship <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Lesser Restoration <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Witch's Spellbook: </strong>ray of sickness, sleep, Tasha's hideous laughter, alter self, and invisibility</li><li><strong>Esmae's Spellbook: </strong>charm person, magic missile, shield, witch bolt, crown of madness, misty step, counterspell, dispel magic, fireball, hypnotic pattern, lightning bolt, blight, Evard's black tentacles, polymorph, cloudkill, disintegrate, and finger of death</li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details><details><summary>Escape from the Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You are free of the Demiplane of Dread and may remove the <strong>The Demiplane of Dread</strong> story award. If you later return to Barovia, you regain the story award again and must find a new way out.</p><p>If you have the <strong>Touched by the Mists</strong> story award, you fall into a magical coma upon returning and lose 10 downtime days for each dark gift you possess. You must pay life style for each of these days once you awake to eat, repair gear, etc., from while you were out. Upon waking (if you ever do…), you lose the <strong>Touched by the Mists</strong> story award.</p></details><details><summary>The True Meaning of Love</summary><p>You have defeated Esmae Amarantha and once again caged the Evening Glory. You are true warrior of fate and love and are marked as such. You gain advantage on Charisma checks made with followers of the goddess Sûne. You may cross this favor out to succeed on a saving throw against a charm effect that you have failed.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-13</guid><title>DDAL04-13 - The Horseman</title><description>Ring of Animal Influence, a potion, 2 scrolls, and 3 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-13</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Horseman</h1><p>An unknown force is inciting the people and creatures of the idyllic Greenhall to commit horrific acts of murder and carnage. Can the adventurers quell the towering rage of the rampaging Horseman? Part Thirteen of <em>Misty Fortunes and Empty Hearts</em>.</p><p>A 2-Hour Adventure for 5th–10th Level Characters</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ring of Animal Influence <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Flying <em>very rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Water Breathing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Water Walk <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details><details><summary>Impression of Obsession</summary><p>You have been subjected to the spiritual impressions of a witch called Esmae Amarantha. Though you aren’t sure how, you have been told that the impressions will be enough for you to harness the power of an ancient locket to somehow sap the witch of her power.</p></details><details><summary>Quivering with Anger</summary><p>You stood idle by while elves of the Quivering Forest were slaughtered by animated plants. Because of this, those that survived have broken their pact with the hag, Jeny Greenteeth. In her anger, she forevermore refuses to provide you with any spellcasting services.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-12</guid><title>DDAL04-12 - The Raven</title><description>Bonds of Fear (Dimensional Shackles), a potion, a scroll, and 3 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-12</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Raven</h1><p>The Bloodhand orcs have a prisoner that may hold the answers to the strange goings on and the key to stopping the enemy. What can you do to convince them to hand the prisoner over? Part Twelve of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 5th–10th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Bonds of Fear (Dimensional Shackles) <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Alarm <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Bird’s Eye View</summary><p>Time spent upon the heights of Rookscrag give you a new perspective on the surrounding countryside. If you spend 10 downtime days meditating upon the summit, you may later spend an action to gain the one-time effects of a <em>commune with nature</em> spell. Remove this story award from your logsheet once it's been used.</p></details><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details><details><summary>Friends in High Places</summary><p>The ravens of Rookscrag share many secrets with those able to tease out their meaning. If you spend 10 downtime days listening to the cackling of ravens, you may later spend an action to gain the one-time effects of a <em>legend lore</em> spell. Remove this story award from your logsheet once it's been used.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-11</guid><title>DDAL04-11 - The Donjon</title><description>Dagger of Venom, Gemstone Necklace, 2 potions, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-11</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Donjon</h1><p>The village of Orașnou is panicked when a group of Bloodhand orcs appear at the edge of the woods. They bring news and an unusual request that reveals a new foe. Part Eleven of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A 4-Hour Adventure for 5th–10th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Dagger of Venom <em>rare</em></li><li>Gemstone Necklace <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-10</guid><title>DDAL04-10 - The Artifact</title><description>Driftglobe, Wand of Binding, 2 scrolls, a spellbook, and 2 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-10</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Artifact</h1><p>An expedition to the Amber Temple reveals another major minion of the enemy and uncovers a secret weapon that may help defeat them. Part Ten of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A Four-Hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Driftglobe <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Wand of Binding <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Scroll of Protection (Plants) <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Scroll of Protection (Poison) <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Handmade Spellbook: </strong>Spellbook will be constructed with up to ten spells from the same school from the wizard's spell list as requested by the player.</li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details><details><summary>Is That a Dead Wizard in Your Pocket?</summary><p>You are playing host to the spirit of a long dead—and rather eccentric—ghost. While the ghost does not control you, you pick up some of its characteristics. As long as you have this story award, you gain a personality trait, ideal, bond, or flaw of your choice that reflects the ghost’s subtle influence on your personality. You may remove this story award at any time by informing the ghost that he or she is no longer welcome (politely or otherwise).</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-09</guid><title>DDAL04-09 - The Tempter</title><description>Glamoured Studded Leather, a scroll, and 2 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-09</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Tempter</h1><p>The people of Orașnou are desperate. The village is on the brink of starvation and has little chance of surviving the harsh winter. Even if they had enough food and supplies, Lord Strahd’s taxes are due, and the ruler of Barovia does not accept excuses as payment. The Burgomaster and others in the village have recently learned of a wealthy estate that might have enough resources to solve both of Orașnou’s problems. It is a temptation he cannot afford to resist or can he? Part Nine of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 5th–10th level Characters</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Glamoured Studded Leather <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Mass Cure Wounds <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details><details><summary>Cursed by Greed</summary><p>Blinded by greed, you have been cursed by an ancient family. Because of this, you are affected by a permanent <em>bestow curse</em>. While so cursed, you have disadvantage on ability checks and saving throws made with an ability score determined randomly by the Dungeon Master. This curse can only be removed by spending 10 downtime days returning the Fidatov family treasure to the crypt or by leaving the Demiplane of Dread.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-08</guid><title>DDAL04-08 - The Broken One</title><description>Ring of Spell Storing and 2 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-08</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Broken One</h1><p>The village of Orașnou is buried in winter's snows and facing starvation. An unseen beast has ravaged the livestock culled to pay Lord Strahd's tax and the village is thrown into panic and chaos. Can you find the monster and save the village from starvation, or worse? Part eight of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A two-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ring of Spell Storing <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details><details><summary>You Murderer!</summary><p>You have killed a local villager. As a result, you are distrusted (and likely even hated) by the survivors of Eugen’s attacks. For so long as you possess this story award, all of your Charisma (Deception or Perception) checks against a local of Orașnou are made with disadvantage. Additionally, all prices for any purchases or services in the village are doubled.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-07</guid><title>DDAL04-07 - The Innocent</title><description>Cape of the Mountebank, a potion, a scroll, a spellbook, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-07</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Innocent</h1><p>The mists have led you deep into Glumpen Swamp to a den of great evil. Within, the unliving son of an unliving god awaits the peace of death that eternally eludes him. Will you grant him his rest, or realize the part he is to play in things to come? Part Seven of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A Four-Hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Cape of the Mountebank <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Flame Strike <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Brass-Ring Spellbook: </strong>fog cloud, mage armor, shield, blindness/deafness, crown of madness, hold person, suggestion, fear, hypnotic pattern, greater invisibility, Bigby's hand, and mislead</li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-06</guid><title>DDAL04-06 - The Ghost</title><description>Boots of Elvenkind, 3 potions, a scroll, 3 story awards, and one other item</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-06</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Ghost</h1><p>Old hatreds die hard, but sometimes it is necessary to set aside petty, personal disagreements for the greater good. The hag, Jeny Greenteeth, is wise and may prove instrumental in the troubles that lay ahead. Your task will not be easy, however; the dark forces of Barovia have agents everywhere, and eyes from beyond the grave no doubt watch your every move. Part Six of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A Four‐Hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Boots of Elvenkind <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Antitoxin (vial) <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Resistance (Cold) <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Detect Thoughts <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details><details><summary>Enmity of Jeny Greenteeth</summary><p>You don’t cross a hag like Jeny and get away without paying the price. For so long as you possess this story award, Jeny charges you 50% more for any spellcasting services that she provides. In addition, you may not use the alternate methods of payment detailed in the <em>Adventurers League Dungeon Master’s Guide</em>.</p></details><details><summary>Escape from the Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have been escorted out of Barovia by a family of Vistani. The trip is long and arduous, however. Once free, however, you must spend <strong>80 downtime days</strong> traversing the width and breadth of Faerûn in search of the mysterious mists if you wish to return to Barovia. Once you have returned, you once more regain <strong>The Demiplane of Dread</strong> story award and must find a new way out of Barovia.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-05</guid><title>DDAL04-05 - The Seer</title><description>Wind Fan and 3 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-05</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Seer</h1><p>The time has come to venture beyond the village of Orașnou and explore the realm of Barovia. However, in your travels, you happen across an unusual tribe of people--distrusted denizens of the Demiplane of Dread. Do the Vistani truly possess the ability to see the future, or is it simple parlor tricks and deceit? Part Five of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A Two-Hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Wind Fan <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Cunning Insight</summary><p>The Vistani are quite good at reading people. If you spend 10 downtime days learning from the Vistani, you may invoke it at any point in the future, granting advantage to all attack rolls made during your turn. Remove this story award from your logsheet once it's been used.</p></details><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details><details><summary>Trackless Travel</summary><p>Some Vistani know secrets to conceal their passage through the wilderness. If you spend 10 downtime days learning these secrets, you can apply them during future travel. For one day you choose in the future, each creature you choose within 30 feet of you (including you) can't be tracked except by magical means and leaves behind no tracks nor other traces of its passage. Remove this story award from your logsheet once it's been used.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-04</guid><title>DDAL04-04 - The Marionette</title><description>Eyes of Charming, 6 potions, a scroll, 4 story awards, and 3 other items</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-04</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Marionette</h1><p>A Vistani fortuneteller has called you out by name during the Burgomaster’s private reading. She raved of an army of the dead, a delicate powderbox, and a beautiful yet dangerous woman. Now the Burgomaster wants to know why you’re more important than he is… Part Four of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A Four-Hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Eyes of Charming <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Acid (vial) <em>common</em></li><li>2 x Alchemist's fire (flask) <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Climbing <em>common</em></li><li>5 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Animate Dead <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details><details><summary>Eye of the Raven</summary><p>You have aided a member of the mysterious and elusive Order of the Feather. Somewhere, a bird is thinking fondly of you.</p></details><details><summary>Trust of the Burgomaster</summary><p>You have aided the Burgomaster of Orașnou. News travels fast. You gain advantage on ability checks that involve negotiations with any Burgomaster in Barovia.</p></details><details><summary>Ire of the Burgomaster</summary><p>You have slighted the Burgomaster of Orașnou. News travels fast. You gain disadvantage on ability checks that involve negotiations with any Burgomaster in Barovia.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-03</guid><title>DDAL04-03 - The Executioner</title><description>Wolfskin Cap (Hat of Disguise), 3 potions, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-03</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Executioner</h1><p>The locals are spreading rumors of the emergence of an age-old relic in a remote farming village. Surely you won’t be the only one to seek it, but can you afford to not be successful in this mission? And why haven’t they claimed it for themselves? Part Three of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A Two-Hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Wolfskin Cap (Hat of Disguise) <em>uncommon</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-02</guid><title>DDAL04-02 - The Beast</title><description>Whip of Warning, 3 scrolls, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-02</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Beast</h1><p>Something strange is afoot within the Quivering Forest. So much so that even the elves of Greenhall have left their homes to seek out help from their newfound neighbors. But, their tales of a strange beast are not earning them any favors; especially among the Vistani, whom the elves suspect are to blame for their ills. Return once more to the Quivering Forest and learn the terrifying truth! Part Two of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 1st–4th level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Whip of Warning <em>uncommon</em></li><li>3 x Spell Scroll of Create Bonfire <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-01</guid><title>DDAL04-01 - Suits of the Mist</title><description>3 potions, a scroll, 3 story awards, and 2 other items</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal04-01</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Suits of the Mist</h1><p>Strange things are afoot in the Moonsea. The factions have called all those willing and able to investigate strange occurrences in the region surrounding Phlan. Dark whispers and unseen terrors lurk in the misty shadows between this world and someplace much more sinister. Unveil the horrors before it is too late! Part one of <em>Misty Fortunes and Absent Hearts</em>.</p><p>Five, 1‐Hour Mini‐Adventures for 1st and 2nd Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>2 x Holy water (flask) <em>common</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Protection from Evil and Good <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Aya Knows What You Did</summary><p>At some point during the adventure, you kept something valuable that didn’t belong to you, and a rather powerful mage found out. Returning the gems (or their equivalent value) removes this story award. This may have implications in future adventures.</p></details><details><summary>The Demiplane of Dread</summary><p>You have traversed the mists and now find yourself in the Demiplane of Dread and, until this story award is removed, you are unable to leave. So long as you are trapped, you cannot participate in any adventure or event that takes place outside of Barovia. Tread carefully during your time here, the Dark Powers are watching.</p></details><details><summary>A Fine, Feathered Friend</summary><p>Having befriended the strange raven Esselios, if you are capable of casting <em>find familiar</em> you may take the talkative raven in that role. In addition to the other benefits of having a familiar, Esselios offers the following:</p><ul><li>His Intelligence is 4 (‐3) and he can speak Orc and Elvish in addition to Common.</li></ul><ul><li>He grants advantage on checks regarding Orc history, religion, and culture.</li></ul><ul><li>He sometimes gets moody and petulant, muttering to himself in a language no one understands—even through the use of <em>comprehend languages</em>.</li></ul></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-16</guid><title>DDEX03-16 - Assault on Maerimydra</title><description>Demon Armor, Robe of Stars, Quarterstaff, +1, Shortbow, +1, 7 potions, 8 scrolls, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-16</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Assault on Maerimydra</h1><p>With allies gained from denizens of the Underdark, the former drown enclave of Szith Morcane is on the precipice of being retaken. During the battle for Szith Morcane, secrets of the drow community are revealed. What will you do with this knowledge, and how will it affect the outcome of the conflict?</p><p>A eight-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Demon Armor <em>very rare</em></li><li>Robe of Stars <em>very rare</em></li><li>Quarterstaff, +1 <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Shortbow, +1 <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Heroism <em>rare</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Superior Healing <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Commune <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Heal <em>very rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Invisibility <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Lesser Restoration <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Mass Cure Wounds <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Protection from Poison <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Suggestion <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Wall of Force <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Shared Valor</summary><p>Your efforts to gather forces for the Assault on Maerimydra have resonated throughout your faction. When you fail in a faction assignment or special mission, you may choose to void this favor and instead succeed. This does not grant you any rewards (XP, gp, items, story awards, etc.) that might be associated with success, but does count as a success for gaining renown or tracking success of special missions.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-15</guid><title>DDEX03-15 - Szith Morcane Unbound</title><description>Ring of Protection, Potion of Greater Healing, a spellbook, and 2 other items</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-15</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Szith Morcane Unbound</h1><p>With allies gained from denizens of the Underdark, the former drown enclave of Szith Morcane is on the precipice of being retaken. During the battle for Szith Morcane, secrets of the drow community are revealed. What will you do with this knowledge, and how will it affect the outcome of the conflict?</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ring of Protection <em>rare</em></li><li>2 x Portion of Fire Breath <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Spider-Hide Spellbook: </strong>web, levitate, darkness, gaseous form, Evard's black tentacles, arcane eye, and passwall</li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-14</guid><title>DDEX03-14 - Death on the Wall</title><description>Bracers of Archery, a story award, and 3 other items</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-14</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Death on the Wall</h1><p>First Lord Torin Nomerthal and several his advisors will be leaving Hillsfar to inspect the Wall with only a small contingent of Red Plumes. The chance to strike is now! Part Two of <em>Six Knives for Torin Nomerthal</em>.</p><p>A two-hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Bracers of Archery <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Assassin's Blood (vial) <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Poison, basic (vial) <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Serpent Venon (vial) <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Friends in High Places</summary><p>You have assisted in the removal of First Lord Torin Nomerthal from office. In his place, you supported ________________________________ in his place. It is possible that they will be able to aid you in the future.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-13</guid><title>DDEX03-13 - Writhing in the Dark</title><description>Rod of the Pact Keeper, +2, Silvered Greatsword, and 4 potions</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-13</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Writhing in the Dark</h1><p>An unexpected envoy arrives in Sporedome and offers to give aid against the fire giants of Maerimydra, if you are willing to help his people with a small problem.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Rod of the Pact Keeper, +2 <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Silvered Greatsword <em>common</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Poison <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-12</guid><title>DDEX03-12 - Hillsfar Reclaimed</title><description>Eyes of Minute Seeing and 4 scrolls</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-12</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Hillsfar Reclaimed</h1><p>The time has come to fight back against Hillsfar. Elanil Elassidil tasks you with uncovering valuable information to be used in a strike against the leader of Hillsfar, First Lord Torin Nomerthal himself. The only problem is that what you need is protected within the walls of the city. Part One of <em>Six Knives for Torin Nomerthal</em>.</p><p>A two-hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Eyes of Minute Seeing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>4 x Spell Scroll of Disguise Self <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-11</guid><title>DDEX03-11 - The Quest for Sporedome</title><description>Half-Plate of Poison Resistance, 2 potions, and 2 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-11</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Quest for Sporedome</h1><p>In the search for allies in the Underdark, you are called upon to travel through the recently opened Waydown sinkhole to find the lost myconid colony of Sporedome. It is said that they once cultivated a strain of mushrooms that could protect one from falling into madness. Can this be the cure for the rapidly spreading onslaught of insanity?</p><p>A two-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Half-Plate of Poison Resistance <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Diminution <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>In League with the Seer</summary><p>You have made a deal with the Sacred Seer—a myconid in the service of Zuggtmoy—to aid in the battle against the giants of Maerimydra. Hopefully, you will not regret this rather foolish choice.</p></details><details><summary>Mmm… Tastes Like Sanity</summary><p>You are given one small, untreated <em>braincap mushroom</em>. When consumed or administered to someone else as an action, the mushroom acts as a <em>greater restoration</em>, but only as it pertains to reducing the recipient's madness level to 0. The <em>braincap mushrooms</em> are potent, however, and if you consume more than one per adventure, you immediately gain 1d4 levels of madness (no saving throw). Cross this story reward off of your adventure log when used.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-10</guid><title>DDEX03-10 - Quelling the Horde</title><description>Wand of the War Mage, +1, 2 potions, and 2 other items</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-10</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Quelling the Horde</h1><p>The Red Plumes have increased patrols in the region surrounding Hillsfar, and a string of disappearances has followed in their wake. Naturally, this has roused the suspicion of the factions. Join your factions and find out the truth behind the missing farmers.</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Wand of the War Mage, +1 <em>uncommon</em></li><li>2 x Alchemist's fire (flask) <em>common</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-09</guid><title>DDEX03-09 - The Waydown</title><description>Canaith Mandolin, a potion, and a scroll</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-09</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Waydown</h1><p>The recent discovery of an entrance to the Underdark has set local leaders on edge. In a display of initiative, the First Lord of Hillsfar has ordered the construction of defensive structures surrounding what locals have begun to call “The Waydown.” You have been charged with escorting an emissary back to his home in the Underdark without alerting the Red Plumes.</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Canaith Mandolin <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Greater Restoration <em>rare</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-08</guid><title>DDEX03-08 - The Malady of Elventree</title><description>Alchemy Jug, a potion, a scroll, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-08</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Malady of Elventree</h1><p>An escaped duergar slave stumbles into the village of Elventree. With her she brings a malady that grips the small settlement in a bout of madness that seems unshakable. Can you find the source of the madness and save yourself and the village’s inhabitants?</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Alchemy Jug <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Superior Healing <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Lesser Restoration <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>A Taste of Madness</summary><p>You drank from the marilith– shaped samovar. The tea was strong and earthy, and just as it warmed your body, it has also awoken something within the darker recesses of your mind. Your sleeping thoughts are haunted by dark whispers and the caresses of a six-fingered hand…</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-07</guid><title>DDEX03-07 - Herald of the Moon</title><description>Shadowsong (Oathbow), 2 potions, a scroll, and a spellbook</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-07</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Herald of the Moon</h1><p>Elanil Elassidil, an elf bard of no small legacy, has put out a call for trustworthy agents. It is time, it seems, for a quietly hidden piece of elven history to become known to the world. Meira Faerenduil, lost knight of Myth Drannor, has been discovered, and must be brought back to civilization.</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Shadowsong (Oathbow) <em>very rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Animal Friendship <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Climbing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Scroll of Protection (Plants) <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Ilztoj's Spellbook: </strong>mage armor, magic missile, shield, witch bolt, alter self, misty step, web, fly, lightning bolt, Evard's black tentacles, greater invisibility, and cloudkill</li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-06</guid><title>DDEX03-06 - No Foolish Matter</title><description>Pipes of the Sewers and a potion</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-06</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>No Foolish Matter</h1><p>Some of the hamlets outlying Hillsfar have been struck by an odd malady. Rumor has it a traveling carnival visited those hamlets before the disease struck. Does coincidence not equal causation or is something sinister afoot?</p><p>A two-hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Pipes of the Sewers <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-05</guid><title>DDEX03-05 - Bane of the Tradeways</title><description>Shield, +1, 3 potions, and 2 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-05</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Bane of the Tradeways</h1><p>Times are hard in the Hillsfar countryside, especially for those of non-human ancestry. Unscrupulous merchants in league with the hated Red Plumes bleed local farmers and artisans dry. Perhaps some of those loot-laden caravans coming and going from Hillsfar could use a bit of liberation?</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Shield, +1 <em>uncommon</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Heroism <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Oh, What a Slaver You'll Make</summary><p>Word has spread about your involvement in the sale of captive Hillfarians to a group of duergar slavers. For so long as you possess this story reward, any Charisma (Persuasion) checks you make involving the commonfolk of the Hillsfar area are made with disadvantage. Conversely, any Charisma (Intimidation) checks you make with the same are made with advantage.</p></details><details><summary>Boon of Bitterwood</summary><p>You have aided the farmers of the Hillsfar region by revealing and putting an end to a slave trade network operated by some corrupt Red Plume soldiers. Anytime you enter a tavern in the Moonsea region, excluding Hillsfar proper, roll a d20. On a roll of 15 or higher you are recognized by someone as a champion of the Hillfarian farmers. You are treated to a drink, Dragon’s Breath Brandy if available, and your heroics are loudly proclaimed.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-04</guid><title>DDEX03-04 - It's All in the Blood</title><description>Ioun Stone of Regeneration, 13 potions, 7 scrolls, a spellbook, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-04</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>It's All in the Blood</h1><p>Rumors of faceless demonic creatures have been steadily rising in the Hillsfar region, and it is said that far below the surface of Faerun, nestled in the bowels of the underdark, ancient terrors are stirring. The imperiled drow of Szith Morcaine have extended an intriguing offer, but can the drow be trusted, and for how long?</p><p>An eight-hour adventure for 11th–16th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ioun Stone of Regeneration <em>legendary</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Fire Giant Strength <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Flying <em>very rare</em></li><li>4 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Heroism <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Invulnerability <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Resistance <em>uncommon</em></li><li>4 x Potion of Superior Healing <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Cone of Cold <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Fire Shield <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Globe of Invulnerability <em>very rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Hold Monster <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Prismatic Spray <em>very rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Stoneskin <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of True Seeing <em>very rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Gabber Forth's Spellbook: </strong>detect magic, mage armor, magic missile, shield, mirror image, Maximillian's earthen grasp, see invisibility, counterspell, slow, fireball, greater invisibility, polymorph, stoneskin, cone of cold, fire shield, immolation, circle of death, globe of invulnerability, forcecage, incendiary cloud, and time stop</li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>A Deal with a Devil</summary><p>You have rescued the imp Pipyap in the giant-controlled city of Maerimydra. Somehow the pudgy fiend finds a way of knowing things that are happening in places he shouldn't be near. Maybe it's his unusual affection for the Material Plane? In exchange for your bravery, he made an offer that you just might be able to refuse.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-03</guid><title>DDEX03-03 - The Occupation of Szith Morcane</title><description>Staff of Swarming Insects, a potion, and 2 other items</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-03</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Occupation of Szith Morcane</h1><p>Agents of the fire giants of Maerimydra, a city in the Underdark, have overtaken the drow outpost of Szith Morcane. The factions seek out adventurers to free the outpost’s leaders for questioning on the giants’ activities. Can you extricate them before it’s too late?</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Staff of Swarming Insects <em>rare</em></li><li>2 x Antitoxin <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-02</guid><title>DDEX03-02 - Shackles of Blood</title><description>Rapier, +1, a potion, and a scroll</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-02</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Shackles of Blood</h1><p>The Red Plumes have increased patrols in the region surrounding Hillsfar, and a string of disappearances has followed in their wake. Naturally, this has roused the suspicion of the factions. Join your factions and find out the truth behind the missing farmers.</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Rapier, +1 <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Dimension Door <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-01</guid><title>DDEX03-01 - Harried in Hillsfar</title><description>2 potions, 2 scrolls, and 7 other items</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex03-01</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Harried in Hillsfar</h1><p>In the village of Elventree, near the oppressive city of Hillsfar, a recent string of strange occurrences has the locals on edge. The factions have gathered here on the borders of the forest of Cormanthor to determine what’s happening. Is this the machinations of Hillsfar, or something more?</p><p>Five one-hour mini-adventures for 1st–2nd level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>2 x Acid (vial) <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Alchemist's fire (flask) <em>common</em></li><li>4 x Holy water (flask) <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Fire Breath <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Comprehend Languages <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of False Life <em>common</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddep03-01</guid><title>DDEP03-01 - Blood Above, Blood Below</title><description>Belt of Fire Giant Strength, Elven Chain, Ioun Stone of Insight, Javelin of Lightning, Pearl of Power, Rimesplitter (Greataxe, +2), 4 potions, 9 scrolls, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddep03-01</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Blood Above, Blood Below</h1><p>In two different arenas, the call for blood has been sounded. The five factions now seek out bold adventurers willing to brave death in order to draw attention away from Szith Morcane, and in so doing allow a small group to infiltrate the drow outpost and return it to the hands of the drow. What role will you play in this deadly game?</p><p>A special three-hour multi-table adventure for 1st–16th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Belt of Fire Giant Strength <em>very rare</em></li><li>Elven Chain <em>rare</em></li><li>Ioun Stone of Insight <em>very rare</em></li><li>Javelin of Lightning <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Pearl of Power <em>uncommon</em></li><li>4 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>Rimesplitter (Greataxe, +2) <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Scroll of Protection (fiends) <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Scroll of Protection (aberrations) <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Animate Dead <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Bestow Curse <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Dispel Magic <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Mass Healing Word <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Magic Circle <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Remove Curse <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Legend Lore <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>What a Horse!</summary><p>You have earned the respect and thanks of a pegasus, a celestial denizen of the Upper Planes. For as long as you treat the creature with respect and stay true to the ideals that it embodies, it remains faithful to you and happily serves you as a mount.</p><p>While he is willing to wear barding, U'dehl refuses to wear heavy armor for fear that people won't be able to properly behold his magnificence. He is also adamant in being provided nothing but the best food and care. For so long as you retain U'dehl's services, you must maintain a lifestyle of no less than Wealthy.</p><p>If, at any time, you perform an evil act in its presence, you must immediately succeed at a DC 16 Charisma (Persuasion) check. If you fail, the pegasus leaves your service at its next available opportunity. The DM has discretion as to what constitutes an evil act and may assign advantage or disadvantage on the check based on the circumstances surrounding the act. The DC of this check increases by 1 each time you are forced to make it.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-16</guid><title>DDEX02-16 - Boltsmelter's Book</title><description>Medallion of Thoughts, a spellbook, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-16</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Boltsmelter's Book</h1><p>A dwarven expedition has stopped in Mulmaster for much-needed supplies. Furgis Boltsmelter, their founder and leader, is looking for some “no questions asked” protection for the duration of his stay in the city. Whatever he is trying to protect may not stay hidden for long. Can you keep his secret treasure out of the wrong hands?</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Medallion of Thoughts <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Elemental Codex: </strong>absorb elements, alarm, earth tremor, illusory script, magic mouth, Maximilian's earthen grasp, silence, erupting earth, meld into stone, Melf's minute meteors, and transmute rock</li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Friends in Low Places</summary><p>You have met a drow mage of Szith Morcane, if he was allowed to copy the items he needed from the codex he sees you in a favorable light. Perhaps one day he will be able (and willing) to return the favor.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-15</guid><title>DDEX02-15 - Black Heart of Vengeance</title><description>Sword of Wounding (Greatsword), 2 potions, and 2 other items</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-15</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Black Heart of Vengeance</h1><p>Aleyd Burral, the Risen Hero of Phlan has sounded the call to battle! Intent on retaking her home of Phlan, Aleyd has amassed a surprising amount of support from the citizenry of Phlan, including that of the High Blade himself. But as lofty as her goals might be, the honor-bound warrior seems willing to sacrifice much in her quest—including everything she once stood for.</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Sword of Wounding (Greatsword) <em>rare</em></li><li>2 x Elemental Gem (Yellow Diamond) <em>uncommon</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-14</guid><title>DDEX02-14 - The Sword of Selfaril</title><description>The Wall of Teeth (Shield, +2), a potion, a spellbook, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-14</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Sword of Selfaril</h1><p>The fabled sword of Selfaril is told to bestow wisdom and power upon whomever wields it, so naturally its discovery has caused quite a stir in Mulmaster. All of this is complicated when a masked benefactor claims to not only know the truth about the blade, but also how it can be used to benefit the oppressed people of Mulmaster. Can it truly change Mulmaster for the better?</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>The Wall of Teeth (Shield, +2) <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Morcant Burl Wood Spellbook: </strong>frostbite, light, prestidigitation, thunderclap, ice knife, mage armor, magic missile, shield, invisibility, Maximillian's earthen grasp, misty step, fireball, haste, Melf's minute meteors, greater invisibility, phantasmal killer, and dominate person</li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Persona Non Grata</summary><p>The High Blade of Mulmaster has branded you a traitor and a fugitive of the law in City of Danger. During any future encounter taking place within the city of Mulmaster, you have a 1-in-4 chance of attracting the attention of a squad of six Soldiery <strong>knights</strong> that immediately attempts to arrest you. Should you be captured, you are incarcerated and eventually executed.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-13</guid><title>DDEX02-13 - The Howling Void</title><description>Balloon Pack, Staff of Withering, Wingwear, and 6 potions</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-13</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Howling Void</h1><p>A storm of unparalleled fury has been ravaging the peaks of the Earthspur Mountains for a tenday, and the Monastery of the Yellow Rose sits in its eye for now. Some monks have fled the monastery to the safety of Mulmaster and beseech you to convince their more obstinate brothers to retreat to the city before the eye of the storm shifts, and the monestary is in terrible danger. Can you brave the elements and convince the monks to escape?</p><p>An eight-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Balloon Pack <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Staff of Withering <em>rare</em></li><li>Wingwear <em>uncommon</em></li><li>6 x Potion of Bottled Breath <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-12</guid><title>DDEX02-12 - Dark Rites at Fort Dalton</title><description>Sentinel Shield, 2 potions, 2 scrolls, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-12</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Dark Rites at Fort Dalton</h1><p>Fort Dalton along the River Lis was long ago destroyed. Now rumors tell of foul cults practicing their dark rites within the fort’s ruins. Are the rumors of elemental cults true or are the rumors a cover for some other sinister plot?</p><p>A two-hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Sentinel Shield <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Absorb Elements <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Augury <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Missing Loved One</summary><p>You have not found your missing loved one as of yet. Anytime you encounter a captive humanoid or an undead creature, roll a d20. On a roll of a 20 you find your loved one. Gain 100 XP and then cross off this bonus from your character sheet!</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-11</guid><title>DDEX02-11 - Oubliette of Fort Iron</title><description>Battle Axe, +1, 2 potions, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-11</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Oubliette of Fort Iron</h1><p>When Fort Iron was taken from the duergar who inhabited it, much of their subterranean quarters were never fully explored. An ancient oubliette has been discovered and its contents have disturbed the miners. Can the mine and the miners be saved from the dangers of the Oubliette of Fort Iron?</p><p>A two-hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Battle Axe, +1 <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Growth <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Seed of Fel Earth</summary><p>You are in possession of the seed of fel earth; a piece of Ogrémoch, the Prince of Evil Earth, himself. Unbeknownst to you, the seed glows faintly while you sleep. While you slumber, those around you can hear the faint, yet distinct rumbling noises of something burrowing closer and closer to you.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-10</guid><title>DDEX02-10 - Cloaks and Shadows</title><description>Winged Boots, 2 potions, and a spellbook</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-10</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Cloaks and Shadows</h1><p>The Cloaks of Mulmaster have taken an interest in your progress, and may be looking to sponsor adventurers for future work. You’ve been offered an interview with one of their ranking members at the Theater of the Stars, but you never know what to expect in the City of Danger.</p><p>A four-hour adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Winged Boots <em>uncommon</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Flying <em>very rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Drakewell's Spellbook: </strong>mage hand, light, message, detect magic, feather fall, jump, shield, sleep, detect thoughts, locate object, rope trick, animate dead, and lightning bolt</li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-09</guid><title>DDEX02-09 - Eye of the Tempest</title><description>Figurine of Wondrous Power (Serpentine Owl), Wand of Lightning Bolts, a potion, and 3 scrolls</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-09</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Eye of the Tempest</h1><p>A storm of unparalleled fury has been ravaging the peaks of the Earthspur Mountains for a tenday, and the Monastery of the Yellow Rose sits in its eye for now. Some monks have fled the monastery to the safety of Mulmaster and beseech you to convince their more obstinate brothers to retreat to the city before the eye of the storm shifts, and the monestary is in terrible danger. Can you brave the elements and convince the monks to escape?</p><p>An eight-hour adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Figurine of Wondrous Power (Serpentine Owl) <em>rare</em></li><li>Wand of Lightning Bolts <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>3 x Spell Scroll of Sending <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-08</guid><title>DDEX02-08 - Foulness Beneath Mulmaster</title><description>Rod of the Pact Keeper, +1 and a potion</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-08</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Foulness Beneath Mulmaster</h1><p>The sewers beneath Mulmaster have always been dangerous, with countless stories of brigands, murderers, and worse that lurk beneath the streets of the City of Danger. But those stories pale in comparison to a new threat under Mulmaster, one brought to light by a strange and disturbing corpse recently found. It is up to you to learn the terrifying truth of what lurks below.</p><p>An adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Rod of the Pact Keeper, +1 <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-07</guid><title>DDEX02-07 - Bounty in the Bog</title><description>Ring of Water Walking, a potion, 3 scrolls, and a spellbook</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-07</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Bounty in the Bog</h1><p>The Soldiery has grown weary of dealing with a particularly nettlesome band of miscreants who have holed up in the Flooded Forest to the south. And so, you have been called upon to quell their activities so that trade along the North Road can resume unmolested. However, in so doing, the truth behind their activities reveal that much more than simple banditry is at hand. Will you be able to stop it?</p><p>An adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ring of Water Walking <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Comprehend Languages <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Silence <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Remove Curse <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Bandit Mage's Spellbook: </strong>charm person, earth tremor, magic missile, shocking grasp, earthbind, hold person, invisibility, and Snilloc's snowball swarm</li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-06</guid><title>DDEX02-06 - Breath of the Yellow Rose</title><description>Ring of Mind Shielding, 2 potions, and a scroll</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-06</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Breath of the Yellow Rose</h1><p>The monks of the Monastery of the Yellow Rose have long cloistered themselves in their home atop the Earthspur Mountains, practicing their strange lifestyle which is rumored to give them longevity. Now, their dietary restrictions and practices of breath control have become the fashion amongst the well-to-do of Mulmaster. But when a few of these lay practitioners start dropping dead from suffocation and starvation, others start to question the validity of the monks’ claims. Is this simply a deadly ignorance, or is there a fell wind blowing through the rich and powerful of Mulmaster?</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ring of Mind Shielding <em>uncommon</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Resistance (Lightning) <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Misty Step <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-05</guid><title>DDEX02-05 - Flames of Kythorn</title><description>Brooch of Shielding</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-05</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Flames of Kythorn</h1><p>During a summer drought, Mulmaster is threatened by a series of arson attacks. As the populace riots, accusations fly blaming Thayans, residents of the ghettos, rowdy sailors, the refugees from Phlan and dozens of others. Can you solve the mystery before the city burns?</p><p>An adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Brooch of Shielding <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-04</guid><title>DDEX02-04 - Mayhem in the Earthspur Mines</title><description>Belt of Dwarvenkind and 3 potions</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-04</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Mayhem in the Earthspur Mines</h1><p>Riddled with veins of precious ore and gem, the Earthspur Mountains to the west have long been a valuable resource for anyone able to mine them. One such mine has gone silent and the only thing more concerning than its long overdue shipment is the fate of the members of the Soldiery sent to discover what has happened to the mine’s workers. Though the mine lay in a region of the Mountains once claimed by a clan of reclusive dwarves, the Ludwakazar clan wouldn’t be so bold as to violate their long-standing peace with Mulmaster. Or would they?</p><p>An adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Belt of Dwarvenkind <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Heroism <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Resistance (Fire) <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-03</guid><title>DDEX02-03 - The Drowned Tower</title><description>Trident of Warning, 2 potions, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-03</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Drowned Tower</h1><p>You are approached by someone claiming to be a member of the Brotherhood of the Cloak investigating unusual incidents involving some of his brethren. Discretion is vital, as there is rumored to be a link between the denizens of the Tower of Arcane Might and one of the elemental cults. Can you uncover the truth?</p><p>An adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Trident of Warning <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Invulnerability <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Resistance (Fire) <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>To Wear the Cloak</summary><p>If your character is an arcane spellcaster, Salvar Brix has offered to sponsor your admittance into the Brotherhood of the Cloak. Though joining the Cloaks is mandatory for any arcanists seeking to stay in Mulmaster for an extended period of time, and sponsorship is not required, Salvar's sponsorship might be a future boon.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-02</guid><title>DDEX02-02 - Embers of Elmwood</title><description>Staff of Charming, 3 potions, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-02</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Embers of Elmwood</h1><p>A derelict raft drifts into Mulmaster’s harbor carrying a young woman. Delirious with hunger, the only words she seems able to speak so far have been “ash and fire.” The only other clue to her identity is an ornate tattoo. Is the woman insane, or is something nefarious at play?</p><p>An adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Staff of Charming <em>rare</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>To Wear the Cloak</summary><p>If your character is an arcane spellcaster, Zora Culkin has offered to sponsor your admittance into the Brotherhood of the Cloak. Though joining the Cloaks is mandatory for any arcanists seeking to stay in Mulmaster for an extended period of time, and sponsorship is not required, Zora Culkin's sponsorship will definitely have its perks.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-01</guid><title>DDEX02-01 - City of Danger</title><description>4 potions, a scroll, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex02-01</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>City of Danger</h1><p>On the southern shores of the Moonsea, the residents of Mulmaster have eked out a living where others would likely have given up long ago—in a bleak city where corruption is rampant and the Church of Bane holds sway. In these five short, introductory adventures, you will travel the breadth of the City of Danger, meet its people, see its sights, and witness firsthand how the city truly has earned its ominous moniker.</p><p>An introductory adventure for 1st–2nd level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>2 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Resistance (Fire) <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Water Breathing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Speak with Animals <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Marked by the Crushing Wave</summary><p>You have been touched by some force. For good or ill, you do not know. This tattoo resembles a stylized tattoo of a crashing wave just beneath your right eye. Any attempts to remove it fail, and should you cover it, it quickly soaks through any nonmagical covering which mildews, rots, or rusts before falling away. The effects of this mark may become apparent in future adventures.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddep02-01</guid><title>DDEP02-01 - Mulmaster Undone</title><description>Bracers of Archery, Cloak of Protection, Necklace of Prayer Beads, Wings of Flying, 8 potions, 8 scrolls, and a spellbook</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddep02-01</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Mulmaster Undone</h1><p>The Cults of Elemental Evil have been unveiled within the City of Danger and in retaliation, they seek to use the fundamental forces of nature to destroy it from within. Join your factions as well as the Blades, Cloaks, Hawks and Soldiers alike in defending Mulmaster against those that would burn, crush, drown, and buffet it into oblivion.</p><p>A special four-hour multi-table adventure for 1st–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Bracers of Archery <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Cloak of Protection <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Necklace of Prayer Beads <em>rare</em></li><li>Wings of Flying <em>rare</em></li><li>4 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>4 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Aganazzar's Scorcher <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Catapult <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Comprehend Languages <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Maximilian's Earthen Grasp <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Mending <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Warding Wind <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Snilloc's Snowball Swarm <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Tidal Wave <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Whitevane's Traveling Spellbook: </strong>blade ward, gust, light, minor illusion, shocking grasp, thunderclap, absorb elements, feather fall, fog cloud, mage armor, gust of wind, hold person, invisibility, fly, gaseous form, lightning bolt, elemental bane, greater invisibility, storm sphere, control wind, geas, and investiture of wind</li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-14</guid><title>DDEX01-14 - Escape from Phlan</title><description>Robe of Eyes and a spellbook</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-14</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Escape from Phlan</h1><p>Three important citizens of Phlan, who stand against the tyrannical dragon that rules, seek to escape and find refuge across the Moonsea. Can you extricate those that are vital to the factions before it’s too late?</p><p>An adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Robe of Eyes <em>rare</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Thayan Red Wizard Ambassador's Spellbook: </strong>fire bolt, light, ray of frost, prestidigitation, detect magic, mage armor, magic missile, shield, mirror image, invisibility, haste, fireball, fly, ice storm, Evard's black tentacles, and cone of cold</li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-13</guid><title>DDEX01-13 - Pool of Radiance Resurgent</title><description>Mantle of Spell Resistance, Moonsea Cults (Book), 2 potions, a scroll, and a spellbook</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-13</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Pool of Radiance Resurgent</h1><p>Vorgansharax rules Phlan, using the Cult of the Dragon to extend his noxious gaze. But the green dragon seeks far more than control of the beleaguered town—ultimate power is nearly within reach. Will he reactivate the Pool of Radiance and ascend to greater prominence amongst his kind? A sequel to DDEX1-10 <em>Tyranny in Phlan</em> and Part Two of <em>Under Emerald Claws</em>.</p><p>An adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Mantle of Spell Resistance <em>rare</em></li><li>Moonsea Cults (Book) <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Gaseous Form <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Dispel Magic <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Ixusaxa's Spellbook: </strong>detect magic, mage armor, magic missile, shield, misty step, suggestion, counterspell, fireball, fly, ice storm, stoneskin, and cone of cold</li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-12</guid><title>DDEX01-12 - Raider of the Twilight Marsh</title><description>Splint Armor, +1, 5 potions, 3 scrolls, a spellbook, a story award, and 10 other items</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-12</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Raider of the Twilight Marsh</h1><p>A black dragon’s treasure horde has been located in the Twilight Marsh, and within it are secrets that hold interest to the factions. With the dragon marauding over the countryside, the horde is left unguarded. Now is the time to plunder its lair!</p><p>An adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Splint Armor, +1 <em>rare</em></li><li>2 x Alchemist's fire (flask) <em>common</em></li><li>4 x Antitoxin (vial) <em>common</em></li><li>2 x Oil (flask) <em>common</em></li><li>2 x Poison, basic (vial) <em>common</em></li><li>4 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Invulnerability <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Haste <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Protection from Energy <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Water Walk <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Uliset Faelgren's Dragonhide Spellbook: </strong>comprehend languages, detect magic, identify, detect thoughts, locate object, see invisibility, clairvoyance, tongues, arcane eye, and legend lore</li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Traded with a Hag</summary><p>Either out of greed, naivety, or sheer ignorance, you traded with a hag and now bear a mark visible only to other fey. Any Charisma (Persuasion) checks made to positively influence non-evil fey are made with disadvantage. In order to remove this mark, the hag that you traded with must willingly return the "payment" you rendered in the trade.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-11</guid><title>DDEX01-11 - Dark Pyramid of Sorcerer's Isle</title><description>Horn of Blasting, 6 potions, 2 scrolls, 2 spellbooks, and one other item</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-11</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Dark Pyramid of Sorcerer's Isle</h1><p>Long unoccupied, the pyramid on Sorcerer’s Isle now flows with strange magical energy, warping creatures and the landscape around it. The Cult of the Dragon and Red Wizards of Thay have taken notice, and it’s up to you to keep whatever power dwells there out of their hands.</p><p>An adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Horn of Blasting <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Acid (vial) <em>common</em></li><li>6 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Dispel Magic <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Gaseous Form <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Dragonborn Mage's Spellbook: </strong>detect magic, mage armor, magic missile, shield, invisibility, mirror image, haste, fireball, fly, Evard's black tentacles, polymorph, cone of cold, and Bigby's hand</li><li><strong>Rorreth's Spellbook: </strong>false life, mage armor, magic missile, shield, invisibility, misty step, web, animate dead, fireball, remove curse, ice storm, stoneskin, cloudkill, and hold monster</li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-10</guid><title>DDEX01-10 - Tyranny in Phlan</title><description>Ioun Stone of Protection, 4 potions, a scroll, a spellbook, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-10</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Tyranny in Phlan</h1><p>The Maimed Virulence has come. The future of the Cinnabar Throne and the lives of the denizens of Phlan are in jeopardy. The Cult of the Dragon rejoices, and the Black Fist is powerless to stop them. How will the factions of the city respond to this threat? Can Phlan be saved this time? Part One of <em>Under Emerald Claws</em>.</p><p>An adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ioun Stone of Protection <em>rare</em></li><li>4 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Sending <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Ixusaxa’s Spellbook: </strong>detect magic, mage armor, magic missile, shield, misty step, suggestion, counterspell, fireball, fly, ice storm, stoneskin, and cone of cold</li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>In Dark Linsa’s Pocket</summary><p>In exchange for her assistance in smuggling more than ten dozen people out of Phlan, you have become indebted to the half-drow rogue, Dark Linsa. Despite how ominous this might sound, she was quite impressed by your actions and may call upon you to perform some important task for her in the future.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-09</guid><title>DDEX01-09 - Outlaws of the Iron Route</title><description>Longbow, +1</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-09</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Outlaws of the Iron Route</h1><p>The Iron Route, an important trade road east of Phlan, is beset by competing bandits. An exiled Black Fist officer leads his band of mercenaries turned cloaked ruffians, while a mysterious dragonborn sorcerer commands screaming savages from the north. In this war over the trade route, the beleaguered merchants are the victims, and Phlan suffers from a lack of supplies. It’s up to adventurers to strike out and reopen this vital route.</p><p>An adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Longbow, +1 <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-08</guid><title>DDEX01-08 - Tales Trees Tell</title><description>Cloak of Elvenkind and a scroll</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-08</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Tales Trees Tell</h1><p>Despite the shaky alliance that exists with the elves of the Quivering Forest, they do not suffer trespas their realm lightly, especially from common folk from nearby Phlan. A woodworker’s recent blunder into the forest might set off a diplomatic incident. Can you help find him and mollify the aggravated elves?</p><p>An adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Cloak of Elvenkind <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Chromatic Orb <em>common</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-07</guid><title>DDEX01-07 - Drums in the Marsh</title><description>a scroll and one other item</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-07</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Drums in the Marsh</h1><p>For the past several nights, drums have been heard on the wind, coming from the Twilight Marsh. Each morning, more turn up missing from the nearby farms, leaving only muddy, clawed footprints heading towards the marsh. Can you help the find the lost and bring justice to the abductors?</p><p>An adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>1 x Keoghtom's Ointment <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Fireball <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-06</guid><title>DDEX01-06 - The Scroll Thief</title><description>Headband of Intellect, 2 potions, 2 scrolls, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-06</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Scroll Thief</h1><p>Scholars Square is a relatively quiet corner of Phlan, but a series of odd thefts have the headmasters of various schools in the area concerned. The headmasters’ pleas for help have gone unanswered by the Black Fist, and the Lord Sage of Phlan decides to reach out to you and your kind to bring those responsible to justice.</p><p>An adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Headband of Intellect <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Dispel Magic <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Hold Person <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Favor of Ellison Berenger</summary><p>Instead of killing him, you have demonstrated mercy towards Ellison. He is thankful--even if you turned him in to the Black Fist. This favor has no immediate benefit, but should he face the adventurers again, their mercy is not forgotten.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-05</guid><title>DDEX01-05 - The Courting of Fire</title><description>Ring of Resistance (Fire) and 2 scrolls</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-05</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>The Courting of Fire</h1><p>An exiled cultist and his kobold minions are spotted searching long-forgotten ruins in the Dragonspire Mountains. Rumors say he looks for a precious gift to give to a fearsome dragon that dwells there. What he hopes to attain with his gift is unknown, but can't be good for the citizens of Phlan.</p><p>An adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ring of Resistance (Fire) <em>rare</em></li><li>2 x Spell Scroll of Flame Blade <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-04</guid><title>DDEX01-04 - Dues for the Dead</title><description>Goggles of Night and 3 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-04</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Dues for the Dead</h1><p>For years, the Most Solemn Order of the Silent Shroud has tended the dead at Valinghen graveyard, p g them a peaceful eternal rest. Now, that rest has been disturbed by a necromancer seeking out a key to re-activate the Pool of Radiance.</p><p>An adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Goggles of Night <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Enmity of Doomguide Yovir Glandon</summary><p>Despite his requests, you were caught stealing from the resting dead or allowed others to do so. Because of this, all members of Kelemvor's clergy in Phlan are highly distrustful of you. So long as you have this enmity, all future Charisma (Deception, Intimidation, or Persuasion) checks made against members of Kelemvor's faithful in Phlan are made with disadvantage. Additionally, the cost for any spellcasting services provided by the clergy is increased by 10%.</p></details><details><summary>Enmity of the Welcomers</summary><p>You slew one or more members of the Welcomers for little more than petty theft. So long as you have this enmity, all future Charisma (Deception, Intimidation, or Persuasion) checks made against members of the Welcomers faithful are made with disadvantage.</p></details><details><summary>Favor of the Welcomers</summary><p>You helped a small group of Welcomers escape from the Catacombs without informing Doomguide Glandon. So long as you have this favor, all future Charisma (Deception, Intimidation, or Persuasion) checks made against members of the Welcomers faithful are made with advantage.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-03</guid><title>DDEX01-03 - Shadows over the Moonsea</title><description>Ring of Evasion and 2 potions</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-03</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Shadows over the Moonsea</h1><p>Life on the Moonsea isn’t easy. Bandits, pirates, and cruel lords dominate the land, threatening those who make an honest living there. Now, a new scourge is prowling the waters: A ghost ship has been striking small coastal villages, leaving its victims whispering about the “eye of the dracolich.” Join the adventure and learn the truth behind this threat!</p><p>An adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Ring of Evasion <em>rare</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-02</guid><title>DDEX01-02 - Secrets of Sokol Keep</title><description>Moonsea Cults (Book), Splint Armor, a story award, and one other item</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-02</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Secrets of Sokol Keep</h1><p>Decades have passed since Sokol Keep was reclaimed, and a small garrison placed there along with a beacon to help guide ships. Now, that beacon has gone dark, and the garrison has disappeared. In Phlan, rumors circulate that something ancient was discovered in the grounds beneath the keep, dating to before the clerics of Tyr built the small fortress. Uncover the secrets of Sokol Keep!</p><p>An adventure for 1st–4th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Moonsea Cults (Book) <em>common</em></li><li>Splint Armor <em>common</em></li><li>Wand of Magic Detection <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Enmity of the Black Fist</summary><p>An innocent man died by your hand during the barroom brawl in the <em>Laughing Goblin</em>. Though you were arrested for your crimes, your faction eventually procured your release. The Black Fist, however, still associates you with your crimes. So long as you have this enmity, all future Charisma (Deception, Intimidation, and Persuasion) checks made against members of the Black Fist are made with disadvantage.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-01</guid><title>DDEX01-01 - Defiance in Phlan</title><description>Enchanted Blue Dragon's Tooth, 4 potions, and 2 scrolls</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddex01-01</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Defiance in Phlan</h1><p>The Cult of the Dragon has come to Phlan, a lawless refuge on the Moonsea. Now, with no significant authority to stop the cult, other power groups in the Realms—the Harpers, Order of the Gauntlet, Emerald Enclave, Lords’ Alliance, and even the Zhentarim—must unite to stop the cult from fulfilling its dark purpose in the city. Join the fight by participating in any one of five different missions aimed at stopping the cult.</p><p>An introductory adventure for 1st-level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Enchanted Blue Dragon's Tooth <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Climbing <em>common</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Comprehend Languages <em>common</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Protection from Evil and Good <em>common</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal00-04</guid><title>DDAL00-04 - Winter's Flame</title><description>Chultan Midwinter Candle (Candle of the Deep) and Flurried Furs (Smoldering Armor)</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddal00-04</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Winter's Flame</h1><p>This year’s Midwinter holiday efforts have been met with unusual obstacles: small stockpiles rummaged through, foods spoiling, ale casks leaking, festive clothes torn up, and crucial pembelon fruits missing. With schedules and deadlines rigid, any bigger bumps in the road might result in disaster. Who would want to keep the people of Chult from celebrating this long-revered holiday?</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Chultan Midwinter Candle (Candle of the Deep) <em>common</em></li><li>Flurried Furs (Smoldering Armor) <em>common</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddhc-wdh-03</guid><title>DDHC-WDH-03 - Blue Alley</title><description>Lantern of Revealing, Moon-Touched Sword, Wand of Secrets, 3 potions, and 5 other items</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddhc-wdh-03</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Blue Alley</h1><p>The infamous Blue Alley lies hidden in the heart of Waterdeep. Built by a secretive wizard, it is a magic maze full of tricks, traps, strange monsters, and rich treasure. Countless adventurers have ventured inside to test their bravery and skill, yet few have returned. And now it is your turn…</p><p>A Four-Hour Adventure for Tier 1 Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Lantern of Revealing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>Moon-Touched Sword <em>common</em></li><li>Wand of Secrets <em>uncommon</em></li><li>5 x Amnish Wine (Alchemist's fire) <em>common</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Healing <em>common</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddhc-lmop</guid><title>DDHC-LMOP - Lost Mine of Phandelver</title><description></description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ddhc-lmop</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Lost Mine of Phandelver</h1></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-nbdd01-02</guid><title>CCC-NBDD01-02 - Where Can She Be?</title><description>Clockwork Amulet, Hat of Disguise, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-nbdd01-02</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Where Can She Be?</h1><p>A master criminal has been making her way across the Moonsea, stealing priceless treasures at every stop. It's up to you to trace her steps, find her allies, and stop her before she can claim her final prize.</p><p>A Two to Four-Hour Adventure for Tier 2 Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Clockwork Amulet <em>common</em></li><li>Hat of Disguise <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Do It A Capella</summary><p>You have performed with the traveling a capella kenku bard troupe, Roc Capella. Should you encounter them again, you will be welcome to join in their performance and are treated as part of the band.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-nbdd01-01</guid><title>CCC-NBDD01-01 - Clever</title><description>Portable Hole, 2 potions, and a spellbook</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-nbdd01-01</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Clever</h1><p>A strange new crime family has been growing and tightening its grips on local businesses. Any who refuse their offers are found dead shortly after, torn apart by claws and teeth. Who is behind this wave of organized crime?</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for Tier 2 Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Portable Hole <em>rare</em></li><li>2 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p><h2>Spellbooks</h2><p><ul><li><strong>Tyrant Lizard Transporter’s Spellbook: </strong>alarm, disguise self, illusory script, Tenser's floating disk, unseen servant, arcane lock, enlarge/reduce, levitate, rope trick, fly, gaseous form, nondetection, sending, fabricate, Leomund's secret chest, and telekinesis</li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-gsp01-03</guid><title>CCC-GSP01-03 - Tainted Love</title><description>Cloak of Many Fashions and 2 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-gsp01-03</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Tainted Love</h1><p>Rizgrim, the Great Doomguide of Kelemvor has discovered that the land within the Quivering Forest near the burial site of her friend is slowly being consumed by dark magic. The adventurers have been asked to find the source and eliminate it as soon as possible. Failing on this task could turn her dead friend into a dracolich. Nobody wants that! Right?! Part 3 of the <em>Clover Group Series</em>.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Cloak of Many Fashions <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>In Search of Her</summary><p>You have found and read the journal of Tho’Guroh, containing information on how to find a hag’s dark lair. Whenever you succeed in finding a hag’s lair, a trail of thin mist appears, leading up to the location you are looking for. While the mist is present, you hear whispers of a very convincing old woman telling you to get "samples" from your party members, like a strand of hair, spit, dead skin, fingernails, etc. Remove this story award when you meet Jenny Greenteeth.</p></details><details><summary>Clingy Jelly!</summary><p>You spared the life of an oblex spawn. As a token of appreciation, it separates a part of itself and places a thin translucent layer of star-shaped green goo on your forehead. Whenever you are in combat, the goo stretches and changes shape, becoming a horn. Whenever you die, its shape changes into a small, flat skull. You can remove this story award by casting <em>lesser restoration</em> on yourself.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-gsp01-02</guid><title>CCC-GSP01-02 - Brotherhood</title><description>Pipe of Smoke Monsters and 2 story awards</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-gsp01-02</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Brotherhood</h1><p>Ragvala, an ancient gold dragon and the founder of the Five-Leaf Clover is dead. A funeral ceremony will be held in 3 days before he becomes one with the earth. Rokstasha, his friend and a djinni has asked the help of the adventurers to find the other members of the Five-Leaf Clover if they are still alive and have them attend the ceremony. Don’t be late! Part 2 of the <em>Clover Group Series</em>.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Pipe of Smoke Monsters <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Five-Leaf Clover Initiate</summary><p>A senior member of the Five Leaf Clover has taken a liking of you and made you a junior member of their adventuring group. A magical tattoo of a five-leaf clover has been permanently placed at the back of your right hand. When you put your will to it, harmless green flame erupts from the tattoo and engulfs your hand.</p></details><details><summary>Doomguide of Kelemvor</summary><p>You are now an official priest of Kelemvor, also known as a Doomguide. You have received a set of smoky grey priestly vestments with the symbol of Kelemvor and a cowled cloak with a white domino mask that emanates harmless blue flame whenever you wear it. You also gain the following ideal, "Death is but part of life: fear it not, evade it not, and view it not as evil."</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-gsp01-01</guid><title>CCC-GSP01-01 - A Dragon's Breath</title><description>Dragon's Lullaby (Instrument of the Bards - Mac-Fuirmidh cittern), a scroll, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-gsp01-01</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>A Dragon's Breath</h1><p>Ragvala, also known as the "Coinmaker", is an ancient gold dragon who wishes to mend his broken friendship with his old adventuring buddy. Recently, he has heard rumors that his friend’s old magical instrument has resurfaced in the Quivering Forest. Unable to change shape anymore, the dragon needs the help of skilled adventurers who can join him on his quest.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Dragon's Lullaby (Instrument of the Bards - Mac-Fuirmidh cittern) <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Comprehend Languages <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>Five-Leaf Clover Initiate</summary><p>A senior member of the Five Leaf Clover has taken a liking of you and made you a junior member of their adventuring group. A magical tattoo of a five-leaf clover has been permanently placed at the back of your right hand. When you put your will to it, harmless green flame erupts from the tattoo and engulfs your hand.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-anime01-03</guid><title>CCC-ANIME01-03 - Star Sword, Return!</title><description>Orb of the Stein Rune and 2 potions</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-anime01-03</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Star Sword, Return!</h1><p>With less than two days until the Festival of Stars in Hawksroost, Daern's Blade is still missing, but the adventurers are en route to its resting place. Are they truly prepared for what they find?</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 5th–10th Level Characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Orb of the Stein Rune <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Heroism <em>rare</em></li><li>1 x Potion of Resistance (Poison) <em>uncommon</em></li></ul></p></section>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-anime01-02</guid><title>CCC-ANIME01-02 - Let's Find the Sword, GO!</title><description>Yata Mirror (Shield, +2), 3 potions, a scroll, and a story award</description><link>https://arbron.github.io/adventure-items/adventures/ccc-anime01-02</link><pubDate>Tue, 8 Sep 2020 17:52:48 -0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<section><h1>Let's Find the Sword, GO!</h1><p>After learning that Daern’s Blade, a relic that had protected the town of Hawksroost, vanished centuries ago, Sorrim requires assistance in locating it. An old halfling adventurer has learned rumors of the blade hidden within the Vanishing Hills. These same rumors also say that it may be guarded by something ancient. With the Festival of the Stars only a few days out, can the blade be found and returned in time?</p><p>A Two-Hour Adventure for 5th–10th level characters.</p><h2>Items</h2><p><ul><li>Yata Mirror (Shield, +2) <em>rare</em></li><li>3 x Potion of Greater Healing <em>uncommon</em></li><li>1 x Spell Scroll of Protection from Evil and Good <em>common</em></li></ul></p><h2>Story Awards</h2><details><summary>To Suffer as Ilmater</summary><p>Your character has shown willingness to sacrifice just as Ilmater himself. As a reward, the grace of Sorrim’s deity has been bestowed upon you. While in the town of Hawksroost you have advantage on all checks that require Charisma.</p></details></section>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>